Teiko Middle School
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
Aomine Daiki.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（火神(かがみ)）ふー… ハッ！
（小堀(こぼり)）なっ…
（中村(なかむら)）ういっ！
（森山(もりやま)）リバン！
Rebound!
（小堀）だあっ！
（観客）押し込んだー！
He pushed it in!
We won't lose!
（笠松(かさまつ)）負けるか！
死んでもこれ以上 離されんな！
Don't let them pull any farther ahead!
We'll win!
（日向(ひゅうが)）
勝つ！ 何が何でも突き放すぞ！
Do everything it takes to pull ahead!
（伊月(いづき)）でやあっ！
（観客１）おー アリウープ！
（観客２）15点差ー！
An alley-oop!
They're 15 points ahead!
Kaijo is screwed!
（観客３）海常(かいじょう) 絶対絶命！
The ace's job is to lead his team to victory.
エースは チームを勝たせるのが
仕事っスよね
If I don't play now, I'm not the ace!
今 行かなきゃエースじゃない！
誠凛に…
We'll beat
Seirin!
勝つんだ！
This is Perfect Copy!
（火神）
これは… パーフェクトコピー！
（木吉(きよし)）がっ！
（黒子(くろこ)）あっ…
（黄瀬）でぇいっ！
（小堀）ふんっ！
We were naive to think we could stay ahead.
（リコ）
逃げ切るなんて 考えが甘かった
We can't win without
stopping his Perfect Copy.
やはりこの戦い—
パーフェクトコピーを
止めなければ勝てない！
勝つ！ ここから残り
オレのすべてを懸けて！
We'll win!
I'll put everything I have on the line!
This Time
Kaijo
Seirin
（伊月）き… 黄瀬の
パーフェクトコピーの—
Kise's extending the limit
of his Perfect Copy?
限界が伸びてる？
（リコ）その可能性が高いわ
It's likely.
そうなれば 今の点差は
とても安全圏とは呼べない
That would mean our lead isn't safe anymore.
何か手を打たないと
マジでヤバイわ…
If we don't do something, we're screwed.
くうっ…
（黒子）あの…
（火神）あ…
Um...
There may be a way
あるかもしれません
黄瀬君を 止める方法…
to stop Kise-kun.
（笠松）話しかけられねえ
すげえ集中力だ
I can't talk to him.
He's really focused.
だが正直 今日ほどこいつを
頼もしく思ったことはねーぜ
He's never seemed more
dependable than he does today.
We can do it.
（小堀）これなら行ける！
A comeback is well within our reach.
（森山）逆転は 十分射程圏内だ！
（武内(たけうち)）いいぞ… 流れは来ている
Good. We're in control.
チームの士気も 静かだが高い
The team is quiet, but morale is high.
This is when miracles happen.
奇跡は こういうときこそ
起こるものだ
I see.
（伊月）なるほど…
難しいが タイミングさえ合えば
It'll be hard, but with the right timing...
（木吉）
黄瀬を止められるかもしれない…
We may be able to stop Kise.
Okay!
（日向）よし！
ここからはミスは絶対できねえぞ
We can't afford any mistakes.
Focus, guys.
全員集中しろ！
Even if our plan succeeds,
Kaijo's team isn't just Kise.
（日向）作戦が成功しても
海常は黄瀬だけのチームじゃない
Don't stop until the final buzzer sounds.
試合終了のブザーが鳴るまで
決して気を抜くな
パスや連係は
今まで以上に慎重に—
Be even more careful with
passes and teamwork.
イージーシュートは外したらダメだ
Don't miss any easy shots.
Do everything you can to keep our lead!
何としても
今のリードを守りきるぞ！
行くぞ 誠凛
Let's go, Seirin!
（日向）ファイ！
（誠凛選手たち）おお！！
Fight!
Yeah!
（火神）ああっ しまった
ディフェンスでもか！
Shit! He can use
Akashi's Emperor Eye on defense, too?
赤司のエンペラーアイ！
（早川(はやかわ)）よおし！ あっ！
All right!
（黒子）ハッ！ えいっ
よしっ
Okay!
（森山）ぬああー！
（木吉）しまった！
Crap!
（笠松）
ハア… ハア… ハア… ハアッ！
Don't worry, Hyuga.
ドンマイ日向！ 切り替えろ！
Change gears.
Yeah.
Offensive mistakes are bad,
but this is the bigger problem.
（日向）攻撃失敗もよくねーが
それ以上の問題はこっちだ
頼むぜ！
I'm counting on you.
Stop Kise's Perfect Copy!
黄瀬のパーフェクトコピーを
止めてくれ！
What?
Kuroko's on Kise?
黒子が黄瀬を？
（黒子）ハア… ハア…
Kurokocchi, what do you think you're doing?
（黄瀬）黒子っち…
どういうつもりっスか？
バレバレっスよ 今さら
後ろに火神っちが控えてる
It's obvious.
Kagamicchi's waiting behind you.
狙いは恐らく 前やったときと同じ
You're trying to do what you did before.
Let me pass you and steal the
ball when Kagami stops me.
わざと抜かせて 火神っちで
止めてからのバックチップ
But I've beaten it once already.
けど それだって
そもそも一度破ってる
Surely...
まさか…
You're not trying to use the same move!
前と同じなんてこと
ないっスよね!?
No, it's different this time.
はい 前とは違います
（小金井(こがねい)）イーグルスピア！
（降旗(ふりはた)）もらった！
Eagle Spear!
Got it!
This is...
（氷室(ひむろ)）これは…
Taiga, Kuroko, and Izuki's triple-team!
タイガ 黒子 伊月の
トリプルアタック！
The left side is open.
空いてるのは左…
But Tetsu let him pass on the right,
だがテツはわざと右から抜かせ—
leaving Kise's center
of gravity on the right.
黄瀬は重心が右に残っちまってる
今から切り返すんじゃ遅すぎる
It's too late to cross over now.
（日向）タイミング完璧！
逃げ場はねえ！
The timing's perfect!
There's nowhere to run!
（黄瀬）いよおおー！
（リコ）そんな… 今のは黒子君の
パススキルの応用!?
Impossible...
Did he just use Kuroko's passing skills?
ノーモーションから
スピンの遠心力を利用してパス！
He used the centrifugal force of the spin
to pass the ball from a standstill.
いかん… なんて速さだ！
Crap! He's too fast!
（火神）黄瀬ぇー！！
So high!
高い！
（観客１）うおお！
決まったー アリウープ！
He made the alley-oop!
Kise's unstoppable!
（観客２）黄瀬が止まらねえー！
（武内）よおし！
Yes!
Kagami-kun!
（黒子）火神君！
It doesn't matter what you do.
（黄瀬）
何をしてこようがムダっスよ
今のオレは 誰にも止められない
No one can stop me now.
（火神）強い！
He's strong.
（葉山(はやま)）スッゲー
今のでも止められないのかよ!?
Wow! That didn't stop him, either.
If only that were their only problem.
（赤司）
止められないだけならばいいがな
What?
誠凛は既に
負の連鎖にハマりつつある
Seirin is falling into a pattern of failure.
At this rate, Kaijo will swallow them whole.
このままだと…
一気に呑み込まれるぞ
Looking good, Kaijo!
（観客１）海常！ いいぞー！
（観客２）海常の追い上げ！
They're catching up!
They've got this!
（観客３）イケるぞ！
（観客４）頑張れ 海常ー！
Go, Kaijo!
（森山）でいっ！
（伊月）あっ！
カウンターだ！
Counterattack!
（森山）らしくないな 伊月！
This isn't like Izuki.
He's practically begging
for the ball to be stolen.
取ってくれと
言ってるようなもんだぜ
I'll stop him this time!
（火神）今度は止める！
What?
Could it be?
（火神）これはまさか…
ファントムシュートかよ!?
A Phantom Shot?
（降旗）
そんな… パスだけならまだしも…
No way!
I understand the passes...
But Phantom Shots can't be
made without Misdirection.
（小金井）
ファントムシュートは—
ミスディレクションが使えなきゃ
撃てないはずじゃ…
（木吉）いや… 使っていない！
No, he's not using it!
By recreating the irregular form
黄瀬は変則フォームを再現し—
and shooting a high trajectory
shot like Midorima,
そこから緑間のような高弾道で
撃つことで初速を上げて—
Kise's quick shot flew out
of his field of vision!
視界から外した！
Kaijo's closing the gap!
（観客１）
海常がさらに差を詰めたー！
Kaijo
Seirin
（観客２）
こりゃマジで起きるぞ 大逆転！
They might make a comeback!
Oh, man!
（観客３）ヤベー！
（観客４）行けー 海常！
Go, Kaijo!
（観客たち）海常！ 海常！ 海常！
Kaijo! Kaijo! Kaijo!
ナイスだ！ 一気に畳み掛けるぞ！
Nice! Keep up the pressure!
いてーっス！
Ow!
（小堀）いけるいける！
We can do it!
小堀先輩まで！
Kobori-senpai, you, too?
I'm doing great, too.
こっちも絶好調だ
いつでも持ってこいよ！
Pass me the ball anytime.
Got it.
（黄瀬）ウッス！
（早川）やうっスよー！
Let's go! I'm ready to jump!
（早川）跳ぶっスよー！
（黄瀬）へへ…
Kaijo! Kaijo! Kaijo!
（観客たち）海常！ 海常！
（河原(かわはら)）な 何だよこれ…
What is this?
（福田(ふくだ)）観客のほとんどが
海常を応援してる
Most of the fans are cheering for Kaijo.
これじゃまるで
ウチはヒールじゃないか…
It's like we're the bad guys.
The fans are on Kaijo's side.
海常は完全に観客を味方につけたな
途中エースを欠き それでも
食らいつこうとする懸命のプレー
They subbed out their ace
but desperately hung on.
そして 絶体絶命のピンチに
エースが戻り—
Their ace returned in their time of need,
and now they're catching up.
そこからの怒とうの追い上げ
Anyone would want to root for Kaijo.
応援したくなるのは
当然 海常だろう
Seirin will suffer for it.
こうなると苦しいのは誠凛だ
The fans go wild each time the gap closes.
差が詰まるたび沸き上がる観客
They're delighted when they fail.
ミスをすれば喜ばれ
シュートを決めても歓声はない
No one cheers when they score.
The pressure is rising, and they're
out of their comfort zone.
追われるプレッシャーと
アウェーと化した場内
この中で平常どおりプレーするのは
至難の業だ
It's incredibly difficult to play
normally under these circumstances.
（日向）こっちだ！
Over here!
Hyuga shot an air ball?
（伊月）エアボール！ 日向が!?
（木吉）があっ！
（黒子）フッ！
Nice, Kuroko!
（福田）やった 黒子！
（河原）あぶねー！
That was close!
（観客１）ああ〜
惜しい！
Too bad!
It's not Kaijo's ball!
（観客２）海常ボールならず！
Damn, this is hard!
（日向）くそっ やりづれえっ！
Time out.
（リコ）タイムアウト！
Coach?
カントク？
さっき取ったばっかだよ
We just took one.
Hyuga-kun's words during the last time out...
（リコ）前のタイムアウトでの
日向君の言葉…
We can't afford any mistakes.
ここからはミスは絶対できねえぞ
全員 集中しろ！
Focus, guys.
（リコ）
あのとき 気付くべきだった！
I should've noticed then.
"No mistakes, no failures."
“ミスしてはいけない”
“失敗してはダメ”
こうした思考は体を硬くし—
That kind of thinking tenses you
up, leading to more mistakes.
逆にミスを誘発する
要因にしかならない
そして 一度ミスしてしまえば
もはや悪循環
Make one mistake, and it's a vicious cycle.
Thinking about it leads to more mistakes,
考えるほどにミスを連発し
プレーのクオリティは低下していく
dragging down the quality of your play.
Crap!
（木吉）しまった！
（伊月）木吉がファンブル!?
（日向）やべえ 戻れ！
Kiyoshi fumbled the ball?
Crap! Run back!
（火神）
ハア… ハッ… うおああー！
（黄瀬）遅い！
Too slow!
You barely caught up,
but your stance is a mess!
なんとか追いついただけで
体勢はバラバラ—
You're wide open.
スキだらけっスよ！
Kagami!
（伊月）火神！
（森山・早川）いけぇー！
Go!
でやあぁぁぁぁ！！
（海常コール）
Kaijo! Kaijo! Kaijo!
Pushing, white No. 10!
（審判）プッシング 白10番！
フリースロー ツーショット！
Two free throws!
Of course!
（観客１）
当たり前だー！ 強すぎる！
That was way too strong!
（観客２）
ひょっとして わざとか！
Did he do it on purpose?
（火神）ワリ…
Sorry...
うわー 何やってんだよ 火神！
What is Kagami doing?
それじゃいっそう
ヒールになっちまうよ！
They'll hate us even more.
ハア… ハア… ハア…
（黄瀬）
違う… わざとなんかじゃない
No, it wasn't on purpose.
He's just desperate.
こいつはただ… 必死なだけ
（黄瀬）あ…
（火神）ハア… ハア…
ハア… ヒールだろーが
何だろーが 知らねーよ
I don't give a shit if we're villains.
そんなもんがあって—
Villains only exist and lose
in the world of fiction.
負けるのが
決まってんのは—
フィクションの中
だけだろーが
これはオレたちのドラマだ！
筋書きはオレたちが決める！
This is our story!
We decide how it goes!
あはっ…
（火神）負けるのが
決まってんのは—
Villains only lose in the world of fiction.
フィクションの中
だけだろーが
This is our story!
これはオレたちのドラマだ！
筋書きはオレたちが決める！
We decide how it goes!
あはっ…
（日向）火神…
Kagami...
（日向）クサい！ セリフが！
（火神）え!?
That was lame.
I'm amazed you came up with such a lame line.
よくそんなクサいこと言えましたね
How could you even say that?
一体どの口が言うんですか
（火神）テメーだって—
Well, you said, "I'm your shadow!"
“ボクは影だ”とか
ぬかしてただろが！
オレたちのドラマだ！
It's our story! Our story!
（火神）リピートするな！
Stop saying that!
火神 オマエ—
Kagami, you're a script writer?
ドラマの脚本なんて書けたのか
すげーな
Wow...
（火神）あんたは黙ってろ！
Please shut up...
（火神）いや だから…
（リコ）ふっ…
It's just, you know...
Don't worry about the fans!
周りなんて気にすること
ねーっつーか… 絶対勝って その…
We'll definitely win!
We know. You don't have to tell us.
わーってるよ
（日向）みなまで言うな
（火神）え…
Now I'm relaxed.
おかげで肩の力も抜けた
あと残り２分… 楽しんでこーぜ
Let's enjoy the last two minutes.
日向 それオレのセリフ…
Hyuga, that's my line.
But the situation hasn't changed.
（伊月）とはいえ
ヤバイ状況は変わっていない
We need to do something.
何か手を打たないと…
Excuse me.
（黒子）あの—
Kagami-kun's lame line made
me think of something.
今の火神君のクサいセリフで
思いつきました
Haven't you said enough?
（火神）もういいだろ！
（日向）何をだ 黒子
What is it, Kuroko?
This time I know how we
can stop his Perfect Copy.
今度こそ
パーフェクトコピーの突破口を
Kaijo
Seirin
Seirin, time out!
（記録係）
誠凛 タイムアウトです
You can do that?
（日向）
できるのか？ そんなこと…
I'm not sure.
できるかどうかは分かりません
けど 可能性はあると思います
But it's possible.
パーフェクトコピーの強みは—
Perfect Copy allows him
“キセキの世代”全員の技を
再現し—
to recreate the abilities of all the
members of the Generation of Miracles.
それを状況に応じて
複合・使い分けができることです
He can combine and use them
in response to the situation.
Since he's recreating them,
再現ということは—
they're the same as the
ones we've faced before.
１つ１つは今まで戦ってきた
“キセキの世代”と同じ
そしてウチには彼らと互角以上に
渡り合ってきた選手が１人います
And we have a player who's faced
them as more than an equal.
（葉山）
誰をコピーするか 予測する？
Predict who he's going to copy?
Perhaps "induce" would be
more correct than "predict."
予測するというより—
誘導すると言ったほうが
正しいかもしれない
誠凛が今の涼太を止めるには
それしかないだろう
It's the only way Seirin can stop Ryota.
Misdirection requires
more than just technique.
ミスディレクションには
技術だけではなく—
You must also interpret the actions
and habits of your opponent.
相手の仕草やクセを
読み取ることも必要になる
それゆえ
日頃から人間を観察し—
Since Tetsuya observes people
on a daily basis, it's possible.
訓練しているテツヤならば
可能性はある
He can use the trends and habits of
Kise's play to restrict his next play.
涼太のプレー傾向・クセを見抜き
次のプレーを限定する…
だが バスケットにおいて
プレーの選択肢は—
But depending on the situation,
he has countless options.
状況次第で星の数ほどある
It will be incredibly difficult for even
Tetsuya to manage that in two minutes.
残り２分足らずで
それを実現するのは—
テツヤといえど至難の業だ
観察が必要なら 一度下がるか？
If you need to observe him,
why don't you come out?
いえ ここからは近くで
今まで以上に黄瀬君を見たいんです
No. I want to watch Kise-kun from up close.
しばらくほとんど
戦力にはなりませんが—
I won't be any help for a while,
but will you let me stay on the court?
このままコートに
立たせてもらえませんか？
分かったわ
Fine.
Unfortunately, Kise-kun doesn't
seem to be running out of steam.
残念ながら やはり黄瀬君の体力が
尽きる気配はないし
（日向）どっちにしろ—
Either way, we can't win
without stopping Kise.
黄瀬を止めなきゃ
勝てねえってことだ
なら黒子に託すしかねえだろ
We'll have to let Kuroko handle it.
Let's go! We haven't lost yet!
行くぞ！ 勝機はまだある！
Don't give up before it's over!
全員 最後まで
絶対 諦めんな！
Seirin, fight!
誠凛ー ファイ！
Yeah!
（誠凛一同）オウ！！
（観客）うおっ すっげえ気合い…
They're really hyped up.
気をつけろ
誠凛はこっからが強いぞ！
Be careful.
Seirin's just getting started.
Two free throws!
（審判）
フリースロー！ ツーショット！
（観客１）
おおっ ２本とも決めたー！
He made both!
（観客２）完全に射程圏内だー！
It's totally within reach!
We're counting on you, Kagami.
（日向）頼むぞ 火神
（日向）黒子に黄瀬のプレーを
観察させるってことは—
Letting Kuroko observe Kise means
sending the ball his way
on offense and defense.
オフェンスもディフェンスも—
わざと黄瀬がいるほうへ
ボールを集めるってことだ
But one mistake could cost us the game.
だが一瞬でやられちまったら
観察もクソもねえ
We need to hang on and draw
out all the plays we can.
少しでも多く粘って
１つでも多くプレーを引き出すんだ
ウス
Got it.
（黄瀬）この表情…
やっぱり何か企んでるっスね
This expression...
He's planning something.
（火神）エンペラーアイがある以上
小細工は通用しねえ
Little tricks won't work
against his Emperor Eye.
最高速 フルドライブ！
Full speed drive!
He's fast!
（森山）速いっ！
（早川）よおし！
（小金井）ダメだ—
Yes!
It's no use! He can't pass him!
やっぱり抜けない！
（火神）くうっ！
He stopped at that speed?
（笠松）
あのスピードからフルブレーキ!?
His legs are amazing!
なんつー脚力だ！
（火神）でやあっ！
Go back!
戻れえ！
Will it be Aomine's drive,
Akashi's Emperor Eye, or some combination?
（火神）青峰のドライブか
赤司のエンペラーアイか—
それとも合わせ技か…
くそっ 考えたって意味ねえ！
集中するんだ！
Damn it! There's no point in thinking!
Just focus!
抜きに行かない？ なぜだ！
Why isn't he trying to pass him?
おい まさか…
Could it be?
緑間!?
Midorima?
Crap!
マズい！
（伊月）この局面で超高弾道の
スリーなんか打たれたら…—
If he shoots a high trajectory three now,
滞空時間のロスは計り知れない！
we'll lose time while it's in the air!
黒子の観察材料が
決定的に足りなくなる！
Kuroko will have way less to observe!
He faked Midorima-kun's three?
緑間君のスリーを
フェイクに使うなんて！
They have a lead, but since
Seirin needs time to stop Kise,
（青峰）リードしてるとはいえ—
黄瀬攻略の時間が欲しい
誠凛にとっちゃあ—
一番厄介な技だ
that's the worst move he could use.
That's why his fakes are working.
だからこそフェイクも活きてくる
All his choices give Kaijo
the strategic advantage.
選択肢が多い分
戦略的には海常が有利だぜ
（観客）
うおおー！ １人アリウープ！
A one-man alley-oop!
切り替えろ！
取られたら取り返す！
Change gears!
Let's get them back!
He's already here?
（火神）
もうここまで戻ったのかよ！
（黄瀬）だあっ！
Crap! It's going out of bounds!
（伊月）マズい 出る！
（日向）
諦めるな… 勝つんだ 絶対！
Don't give up!
We have to win!
Hyuga!
（伊月）日向！
（リコ）日向君！ あ…
Hyuga-kun?
I'm okay.
（日向）大丈夫だ
ワリィ 福田
Sorry, Fukuda.
Uh, it's okay...
（福田）あ… いや…
Captain! You're bleeding...
キャプテン！ 血が…
Huh?
口ちょっと切っただけだ
心配すんな
I cut my lip a little.
Don't worry.
Anyway, you do what you have to do.
それよりオマエは
自分のやるべきことをやれ
信じてんだからよ
I believe in you.
はい！
Yes, sir!
Seirin's desperate...
（観客１）誠凛も必死だよ…
（観客２）すげえ…
Amazing...
Don't be beat, Seirin! Keep trying!
（観客３）
誠凛も負けるな 頑張れー！
（観客たち）
誠凛！ 誠凛！ 誠凛！ 誠凛！
Seirin! Seirin!
（観客たち）
海常！ 海常！ 海常！
Kaijo! Kaijo!
Kaijo
Seirin
He made it!
（観客１）決まったー！
（観客２）ついに海常逆転ー！
Kaijo made a comeback!
（笠松）よおし！
（早川）やった〜！
Yes!
All right!
（森山）ハハッ ナイス！
Nice!
（日向たち）
ハア… ハア… ハア… ハア…
ハー… ハア… ハア… ハア…
The next attack is Seirin's last
chance to see Ryota's play.
誠凛は次の攻撃中が—
涼太のプレーを見る
ラストチャンスだ
Whether they succeed or fail,
only Kaijo's attack will be left.
攻撃が成功しようがしまいが—
まず間違いなく
海常の攻撃が残る
If Tetsuya doesn't have an
answer now, Seirin will lose.
ここでテツヤが
答えを出さなければ—
誠凛の負けだ
Preview
You haven't given up yet, have you?
（黄瀬）まだ諦めたわけじゃ
ないっスよね
No. We won't lose.
（黒子）
はい 負けるつもりはありません
（黄瀬）オレはエースだ
誠凛がどんな策で来ても—
I am the ace.
No matter what Seirin does,
I'll lead Kaijo to victory.
必ず海常を勝たせてみせる！
（黒子）黄瀬君は最高の
ライバルです だから—
You are my greatest rival.
The Greatest Player
I'll keep fighting until the end.
最後まで全力で戦います！